Guide to the National Extension Association of Family and Consumer Sciences (U.S.) records, 1933-2009.
National Extension Association of Family and Consumer Sciences (U.S.) records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
National Extension Association of Family and Consumer Sciences (U.S.) records, 1933-2009.
6897
National Extension Association of Family and Consumer Sciences (U.S.).
7.5 cubic feet; 5 reels of microfilm.
Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes minutes of meetings and programs from annual conferences.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The National Extension Association of Family and Consumer Sciences educates and recognizes extension professionals who improve the quality of life for individuals, families, and communities and provide education in food preparation, safety and nutrition, financial management, healthy lifestyles, home and work environment and safety, relationship and parenting skills.
Formerly the National Association of Extension Home Economists (NAEHE)
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes minutes of meetings and programs from annual conferences.
SUBJECTS
Names:
National Extension Association of Family and Consumer Sciences (U.S.).; NEAFCS.; National Association of Extension Home Economists.
Subjects:
Family life education--United States.; Home economists--United States.; Home economics extension work--United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Annual Meeting Programs, 1946-1984 (Box 1)
- Recognitions and Awards Programs, 1944-1984 (Box 1)
- Publications Volume I: News From National; The Letter; The News Letter; The HDA Reporter; EHE Reporter, 1943-1977 (Box 1)
- Publications Volume II: The Reporter, 1978-1984 (Box 1)
- Publications Volume III: The Reporter, 1985-1990 (Box 1)
- Volume I: Minutes of The National Home Demonstration Agent's Association, 1933-1950 (Box 2)
- Volume II: Minutes of The National Association of Extension Home Economists, 1951-1964 (Box 2)
- Volume III: Minutes of The National Association of Extension Home Economists, 1965-1972 (Box 2)
- Volume IV: Minutes of The National Association of Extension Home Economists, 1973-1976 (Box 2)
- Volume V: Minutes of The National Association of Extension Home Economists, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
- Volume VI: Minutes of The National Association of Extension Home Economists, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
- Volume VII: Minutes of The National Association of Extension Home Economists, 1981 (Box 3)
- Volume VIII: Minutes of The National Association of Extension Home Economists, 1982-1973 (Box 3)
- Volume IX: Minutes of The National Association of Extension Home Economists, 1984 (Box 3)
- Volume X: Minutes of The National Association of Extension Home Economists, 1985-1987 (Box 3)
- Volume XI: Minutes of The National Association of Extension Home Economists, 1988-1990 (Box 3)
- 50th Anniversary Program - Awards, 1984 (Box 3)
- 50th Anniversary Program - Exhibits, 1984 (Box 3)
- Fellowships-Applications for Grace Frysinger Fellowship, 1951-1984 (Box 4)
- Volume I: Florence Hall Awards, 1954-1970 (Box 5)
- Volume II: Florence Hall Awards, 1971-1984 (Box 5)
- Volume IV: State Histories of the Extension Home Economists Association-collected for 50th Anniversary, 1984 (Box 5)
- Volume V: Fellowships and Awards, 1951-1958 (Box 5)
- Volume V: JC Penny Awards, 1965-1984 (Box 5)
- Volume V: NAEHE Awards, 1964-1984 (Box 5)
- History of the National Negro Home Demonstration Agents Association (NNHDA), 1957-1965 (Box 5)
- "Reflections of the Past"-series of newsletter articles written for the Association's 75th Anniversary-Compiled by Cheryle Syracuse, 2009 (Box 5)
- Memos,conference booklets, publications, including issues of "The Reporter" and various other records of the organization, 1970-1991 (Box 6)
- Memos,conference booklets, publications, including issues of "The Reporter" and various other records of the organization, 1997-2001 (Box 7)
- Memos,conference booklets, publications, including issues of "The Reporter" and various other records of the organization, 2002-2007 (Box 8)
- NEAFCS Books: "Ordinary Women Extraordinary Service" and "Living Well", 2010 (Box 8)
- Microfilm containing "Reporters" (1943/1977-1993); Minutes (1982/1983-1988/1990); Program Books and Exhibits (1946/1984-1994) and Awards (1944/1984-1994) (Box 8)